Register of the Štefan Osuský Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1901-1974. (Box 11-31)
  - Semenský, Rudolf, 1949 (Folder 27: 70)
  - Serbanesco, D. G. R., 1953 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Serhuys, Max, 1939 (Folder 28: 2)
  - Sert, J. M., 1939 (Folder 28: 3)
  - Seton-Watson, Hugh, 1940 (Folder 28: 4)
  - Seymour, Charles, 1948 (Folder 28: 5)
  - Shoop, Max, 1939 (Folder 28: 6)
  - Sikorska, H., 1943 (Folder 28: 7)
  - Sikorski, Wladyslaw, 1941 (Folder 28: 8)
  - Simon, Pierre J. L., 1950 (Folder 28: 9)
  - Simon, Philip, 1939 (Folder 28: 10)
  - Singer, Robert G., 1939 (Folder 28: 11)
  - Sivel, Václav Josef, 1948 (Folder 28: 12)
  - Skarba, V., 1952 (Folder 28: 13)
  - Skládal, J., 1939 (Folder 28: 14)
  - Sklenář, W. F., 1941 (Folder 28: 15)
  - Sklenovský-Bosý, Bruno, 1948 (Folder 28: 16)
  - Slater Roberts, Aleta, 1948 (Folder 28: 17)
  - Slavíček, B., 1940 (Folder 28: 18)
  - Slavík, Vladimír, n.d. (Folder 28: 19)
  - Slíva, Leopold, 1953 (Folder 28: 20)
  - Slode and Ruskin Schools (Oxford), 1941 (Folder 28: 21)
  - Slovak-American Cultural Center, 1968 (Folder 28: 22)
  - Slovak Committee in Chicago, 1950 (Folder 28: 23)
  - Slovak Evangelical Union, 1950 (Folder 28: 24)
  - Slovak Gymnastic Union Sokol, 1954 (Folder 28: 25)
  - Slovenská Líga v Amerike (Slovak League of America), 1915-1973 (Folder 28: 26)
  - Slovenská Líga v Belgicku (Slovak League in Belgium), 1938 (Folder 28: 27)
  - Slovenská národní rada v zahraničí (Conseil National Slovaque à l'Etranger), 1950-1951 (Folder 28: 28)
  - Slovenská Obrana, 1948-1950 (Folder 28: 29)
  - Slovenské Noviny, 1942-1945 (Folder 28: 30)
  - Slovenský Akademický Spolek Detvan (Slovak Academic Union Detvan), 1939 (Folder 28: 31)
  - Slovenský Hlas, 1937 (Folder 28: 32)
  - Slovenský Lud (Buenos Aires), 1941 (Folder 28: 33)
  - Slovenský Sokol (Slovak Falcon), 1916 (Folder 28: 34)
  - Smutný, František, 1946 (Folder 28: 35)
  - Snejdárek, General, 1939 (Folder 28: 36)
  - Social Service for Czechoslovak Refugees in Austria, 1948 (Folder 28: 37)
  - Société Amicale de Secours des Anciens Elèves, 1939 (Folder 28: 38)
  - Société Anonyme des Hauts Fourneaux et Fonderies de Pont-à-Mousson, 1938 (Folder 28: 39)
  - Société d'Economie Nationale, 1938 (Folder 28: 40)
  - Société d'Instruction et d'Education, 1936-1937 (Folder 28: 41)
  - Société de Secours des Amis des Sciences, 1940 (Folder 28: 42)
  - Société des Amis d'Auguste Comte et de Son Oeuvre, 1938 (Folder 28: 43)
  - Société des Caricaturistes Français, 1939 (Folder 28: 44)
  - Société des Cinémas de l'Est, 1937 (Folder 28: 45)
  - Société Française de Géographie Economique et d'Action Coloniale, 1939-1940 (Folder 28: 46)
  - Société Française de Photographie et de Cinématographie, 1938 (Folder 28: 47)
  - Société Normande de Géographie, 1936-1937 (Folder 28: 48)
  - Sogno, Emile, 1939 (Folder 28: 49)
  - Sommier, Edmé, 1939 (Folder 28: 50)
  - Soren Mackay, Peter, 1940 (Folder 28: 51)
  - Sosnkowski, Kazimierz, 1943 (Folder 28: 52)
  - Soumar, Bohuslav, 1948-1969 (Folder 28: 53)
  - Sourek, Ladislav, 1938 (Folder 28: 54)
  - Souritz, Jacques, 1938 (Folder 28: 55)
  - Souza-Dantas, S. E. de, 1939 (Folder 28: 56)
  - Soviet Union. Posol'stvo (France), 1937 (Folder 28: 57)
  - Spánek, Jiři, 1939 (Folder 28: 58)
  - The Spectator, 1941 (Folder 28: 59)
  - Spence, Reginal, 1941 (Folder 28: 60)
  - Spencer-August, Harmon, 1940 (Folder 28: 61)
  - Spicer, Harold W., 1941 (Folder 28: 62)
  - Společnost pro Vědu a Umění (Society for Arts and Science), 1959 (Folder 28: 63)
  - Spolek Československých Studentů, 1939 (Folder 28: 64)
  - Spolek Studujících Poděbradská, 1938 (Folder 28: 65)
  - Šrámek, Jan., See Career File/Czechoslovak Government-in-Exile/Political trial against Osuský
  - Stach, Alex, 1953 (Folder 28: 66)
  - Stancl, J. G., 1939 (Folder 28: 67)
  - Stankoviansky, Emil, 1943 (Folder 28: 68)
  - Staško, Joseph, 1969 (Folder 28: 69)
  - Stavník, Jan, 1939-1957 (Folder 28: 70)
  - Stefan, Paul, 1939 (Folder 28: 71)
  - Stein, Vilém, 1939 (Folder 28: 72)
  - Steinová, Hana, 1939 (Folder 28: 73)
  - Stekel, E. P., 1937 (Folder 28: 74)
  - Stekr, Karel F., 1954-1959 (Folder 28: 75)
  - Stephan, Raoul, 1939 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Stolarik, Marian, 1967 (Folder 29: 2)
  - Stössinger, Felix, 1939 (Folder 29: 3)
  - Stoupan, Lieutenant, 1939 (Folder 29: 4)
  - Stowarzyszenie Ekonomistov Polskich w Zjednoczonym Krolestwie (Union of Polish Economists in the United Kingdom), 1942 (Folder 29: 5)
  - Strabolgi, Lord, 1941-1942 (Folder 29: 6)
  - Straka, Josef V., 1937 (Folder 29: 7)
  - Strakos, Henry, 1941 (Folder 29: 8)
  - Stránský, Jaroslav, 1954 (Folder 29: 9)
  - Stránský, Pavel, 1966 (Folder 29: 10)
  - Strawinsky, Igor, 1939 (Folder 29: 11)
  - Streit, Clarence, 1939-1968 (Folder 29: 12)
  - Stutz, František, 1937 (Folder 29: 13)
  - Suchan, V., 1940-1956 (Folder 29: 14)
  - Suchý, Oldřich, 1937 (Folder 29: 15)
  - Sudetendeutsche Presse-Briefe (Prague), 1938 (Folder 29: 16)
  - Sunday Times, 1944 (Folder 29: 17)
  - Svatik, John, 1940-1945 (Folder 29: 18)
  - Svaz Československého Demokratického Studenstva (Union of Czechoslovak Democratic Students), 1948 (Folder 29: 19)
  - Svaz Zahraničních Čechoslováků (Union of Czechoslovaks Abroad), 1941 (Folder 29: 20)
  - Švec, Emil, 1948-1953 (Folder 29: 21)
  - Švestka, Miroslav J., 1957 (Folder 29: 22)
  - Svetový Kongres Slovákov (Slovak World Congress) (J. M. Kirschbaum), 1970-1973 (Folder 29: 23)
  - Svoboda, Miloš, 1969 (Folder 29: 24)
  - Svoboda, Vilém, 1956-1958 (Folder 29: 25)
  - Svozil, M., 1948 (Folder 29: 26)
  - Sweeny, Charles, 1939 (Folder 29: 27)
  - Switzerland. Botschaft (France) (Walter Stucki), 1939 (Folder 29: 28)
  - Sykes, Frederick, n.d. (Folder 29: 29)
  - Szalatnay-Stacho, B., 1947-1961 (Folder 29: 30)
  - Szirmai, Tony, Madame, 1939 (Folder 29: 31)
  - Sztacho, Adolf, 1953 (Folder 29: 32)
  - Tabouis, Geneviève, 1938 (Folder 29: 33)
  - Taeni, Selma, 1947 (Folder 29: 34)
  - Tanlay, Marquis de, 1939 (Folder 29: 35)
  - Tannenberg-Tamarina, Elsa, 1939 (Folder 29: 36)
  - Tapie, V., 1938-1939 (Folder 29: 37)
  - Tattegrain, André, 1938 (Folder 29: 38)
  - Taylor Lutheran Parish, 1948 (Folder 29: 39)
  - Telatko, Care, 1939 (Folder 29: 40)
  - Teltsch, Arnost, 1940 (Folder 29: 41)
  - Temple, William D. D., 1943 (Folder 29: 42)
  - Tessan, François de, 1939 (Folder 29: 43)
  - Tesson, M., n.d. (Folder 29: 44)
  - Thayer, Charles W., 1948 (Folder 29: 45)
  - Théâtre des Arts, 1939 (Folder 29: 46)
  - Thébaud, L. R., Madame, 1939 (Folder 29: 47)
  - Thiébaut, Gaston, 1938 (Folder 29: 48)
  - Thierry de Martel, Professeur, 1939 (Folder 29: 49)
  - Thomas, Jeanne, 1939 (Folder 29: 50)
  - Thouvenin, Jean, 1938 (Folder 29: 51)
  - Thuyan, Marcelle, 1939 (Folder 29: 52)
  - Tille, A., 1938 (Folder 29: 53)
  - The Time, 1957 (Folder 29: 54)
  - Tkach, Stefan, 1916 (Folder 29: 55)
  - Toledano, I., 1939 (Folder 29: 56)
  - Tomeš, Antonín, 1937-1938 (Folder 29: 57)
  - Totten, Edward P., 1948 (Folder 29: 58)
  - Touche, A., 1938 (Folder 29: 59)
  - Toynbee, Arnold, 1941-1944 (Folder 29: 60)
  - Traub, Jiři, 1939 (Folder 29: 61)
  - Trémoulet, J., 1939 (Folder 29: 62)
  - La Tribune de Genève, 1958 (Folder 29: 63)
  - Tříska, Jan, 1948-1968 (Folder 29: 64)
  - Trnka, Jaroslav, 1938-1974 (Folder 29: 65)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1939 (Folder 29: 66)
  - Try, M., 1939 (Folder 29: 67)
  - Tsatsaronits, J., 1940 (Folder 29: 68)
  - Tuma, Ladislav C., 1948 (Folder 29: 69)
  - Tunis, John R., 1939 (Folder 29: 70)
  - Turkey. Embassy (France) (Behic Erkin Bey), 1942 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Tvarůžek, O., 1942 (Folder 30: 2)
  - Tyndale, H. G., 1941-1944 (Folder 30: 3)
  - Tyrrell of Avon, Lord, 1940 (Folder 30: 4)
  - Udržal, František, 1937 (Folder 30: 5)
  - Ukrainian National Council, 1952 (Folder 30: 6)
  - Ulrich, Zdeněk, 1949-1952 (Folder 30: 7)
  - Union Bretonne des Combattants, 1939 (Folder 30: 8)
  - Union Civica Internacional, 1957 (Folder 30: 9)
  - Union des Anciens Combattants de la Région du Nord de la Société Nationale des Chemins de Fer Français, 1939 (Folder 30: 10)
  - Union des Officiers Tchécoslovaques, 1939 (Folder 30: 11)
  - Union Française, 1939 (Folder 30: 12)
  - Union Franco-Allemande, 1939-1940 (Folder 30: 13)
  - Union Interalliée, 1939 (Folder 30: 14)
  - Union Internationale des Associations de Presse, 1937 (Folder 30: 15)
  - Union pour la Défense des Peuples Opprimés, 1952 (Folder 30: 16)
  - Union Régionale des Anciens Combattants de la Contrée de Lorette, 1939 (Folder 30: 17)
  - The United Lutheran Church in America, 1956 (Folder 30: 18)
  - United Press Associations, 1948 (Folder 30: 19)
  - United Nations, 1948-1953 (Folder 30: 20)
  - United States. Army, 1961 (Folder 30: 21)
  - United States. Central Intelligence Agency, 1959 (Folder 30: 22)
  - United States. Congress. Senate, 1953-1963 (Folder 30: 23)
  - United States. Consulate (Paris) (Thomson), 1939 (Folder 30: 24)
  - United States. Department of Commerce, 1949 (Folder 30: 25)
  - United States. Department of Labor, 1948 (Folder 30: 26)
  - United States. Department of State (Robert Murphy), 1944-1963 (Folder 30: 27)
  - United States. Embassy (France)(William C. Bullitt), 1937-1952 (Folder 30: 28)
  - United States. Embassy (Great Britain), 1941-1944 (Folder 30: 29)
  - United States. Library of Congress, 1956 (Folder 30: 30)
  - United States Associates, 1949 (Folder 30: 31)
  - Université de Dijon, 1938 (Folder 30: 32)
  - Université de Paris, 1938 (Folder 30: 33)
  - Université Populaire de Lille, 1938 (Folder 30: 34)
  - University of Chicago, 1950-1957 (Folder 30: 35)
  - University of Chicago Alumni Association, 1943-1945 (Folder 30: 36)
  - University of Cincinnati, 1949 (Folder 30: 37)
  - University of Edinburgh, 1941 (Folder 30: 38)
  - University of Kansas City, 1948 (Folder 30: 39)
  - University of London. School of Slavonic and East European Studies, 1944 (Folder 30: 40)
  - University of Oxford, n.d. (Folder 30: 41)
  - University of Washington, 1947-1968 (Folder 30: 42)
  - Untersuchungsausschuss Freiheitlicher Juristen der Sowjetzone, 1952 (Folder 30: 43)
  - Ústřední Svaz Československého Studenstva v Exilu (National Union of Czechoslovak Students in Exile), 1954 (Folder 30: 44)
  - Valayer, Paul, 1938-1939 (Folder 30: 45)
  - Valenta, Oldřich, 1939 (Folder 30: 46)
  - Valéri, Valério, 1939 (Folder 30: 47)
  - Valyi, Felix, 1938 (Folder 30: 48)
  - Van Dyke, Vernon, 1948 (Folder 30: 49)
  - Vanderpyl, 1939 (Folder 30: 50)
  - Vaněček, Václav, 1938 (Folder 30: 51)
  - Vaněčková, Milena, 1937 (Folder 30: 52)
  - Vaněk, Vladimír, 1939-1964 (Folder 30: 53)
  - Vánek, Zdeněk, 1939 (Folder 30: 54)
  - Vanier, C. P., 1940-1941 (Folder 30: 55)
  - Vanouš, Arthur, 1957 (Folder 30: 56)
  - Vansittart, Robert, 1941 (Folder 30: 57)
  - Varsik, Vlado, 1938 (Folder 30: 58)
  - Vasseur, Raphael, 1940 (Folder 30: 59)
  - Vaucher, Robert, 1940 (Folder 30: 60)
  - Vaux Phalipay, Madame de, 1939 (Folder 30: 61)
  - Vavasseur, R., 1938 (Folder 30: 62)
  - Vaxelaire, Baron de, 1937 (Folder 30: 63)
  - Veniamin, V., 1953 (Folder 30: 64)
  - Veniselos, Madame, 1939 (Folder 30: 65)
  - Vergé, Arsène, 1939 (Folder 30: 66)
  - Verlag für Internationalen Kulturaustausch (IKULTA), 1957 (Folder 30: 67)
  - Verrier, Madeleine le, 1937-1940 (Folder 30: 68)
  - "La Versaillaise," Société Amicale de Secours Mutuels des Officiers Anciens, 1938-1939 (Folder 30: 69)
  - Vesnitch, Madame, 1940 (Folder 30: 70)
  - Vey, M., 1939 (Folder 30: 71)
  - Veyssière, G., 1938 (Folder 30: 72)
  - Viard, L. R., General, 1939 (Folder 30: 73)
  - La Vie des nations, 1938 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Vienne, Louis de, 1939 (Folder 31: 2)
  - Villey, 1938-1939 (Folder 31: 3)
  - Vísek, Vladimir, 1938 (Folder 31: 4)
  - Visoianu, Constantin, 1947 (Folder 31: 5)
  - Vitáček, V. R., 1963-1964 (Folder 31: 6)
  - Vlach, Robert, 1957 (Folder 31: 7)
  - Vogue, Marquis de, 1939 (Folder 31: 8)
  - Voix européennes, 1938 (Folder 31: 9)
  - Vokac, Lev, 1937-1938 (Folder 31: 10)
  - Voyenne, André, 1938 (Folder 31: 11)
  - Voženílek, Josef, 1937-1949 (Folder 31: 12)
  - Všehrd, 1937 (Folder 31: 13)
  - Vucetic, Mato, 1956 (Folder 31: 14)
  - Vuyk, Madame, 1939 (Folder 31: 15)
  - Waldmuller, Josef, n.d. (Folder 31: 16)
  - Waleffe, Madame de, 1939 (Folder 31: 17)
  - Walter, Emil, 1956-1957 (Folder 31: 18)
  - Walters, Frank, 1940 (Folder 31: 19)
  - Warren, Comte de, 1940 (Folder 31: 20)
  - Watson, Miss, 1939 (Folder 31: 21)
  - Weiler, Paul-Louis, 1939 (Folder 31: 22)
  - Weill, Julien, 1939 (Folder 31: 23)
  - Weill-Goudchaux, Madame, 1937 (Folder 31: 24)
  - Weininger, Richard, 1939 (Folder 31: 25)
  - Weisl, Edwin L., 1948 (Folder 31: 26)
  - Weiss, Louise, 1939-1948 (Folder 31: 27)
  - Welles, Sumner, 1940-1949 (Folder 31: 28)
  - Wendel, Maurice de, 1939 (Folder 31: 29)
  - Wenlock, 1940-1941 (Folder 31: 30)
  - Western Union Telegraph Company, 1943 (Folder 31: 31)
  - Western World Magazine, 1957-1958 (Folder 31: 32)
  - Westfield College, 1942 (Folder 31: 33)
  - White, H. A., 1944-1945 (Folder 31: 34)
  - Wiadomosci Polskie, 1943 (Folder 31: 35)
  - Wielmozny, Jasnie, 1944 (Folder 31: 36)
  - Wiener, F., 1939 (Folder 31: 37)
  - Williams, Clayton E., 1940-1941 (Folder 31: 38)
  - Wilner, František, 1939 (Folder 31: 39)
  - Wilson, Edwin C., 1939 (Folder 31: 40)
  - Winaut, John G., 1945 (Folder 31: 41)
  - Winter, Ludovít and Emerich, 1937 (Folder 31: 42)
  - Wolfe and Hollander, Ltd., 1943 (Folder 31: 43)
  - Wolford, Leo T., 1943 (Folder 31: 44)
  - Women for Freedom of Europe, Inc., n.d. (Folder 31: 45)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1939 (Folder 31: 46)
  - Woodruff, Douglas, 1940-1944 (Folder 31: 47)
  - Woolston, William J., 1958 (Folder 31: 48)
  - Workers' Educational Association, 1941-1943 (Folder 31: 49)
  - Workers' Educational Trade Union Committee, 1941 (Folder 31: 50)
  - World Association of Girl Guides and Girl Scouts, 1940 (Folder 31: 51)
  - World Jewish Congress, 1939 (Folder 31: 52)
  - Worliczek, 1942-1944 (Folder 31: 53)
  - Wurmfeldová, Berta, 1938 (Folder 31: 54)
  - Yugoslavia. Poslanstvo (United States)? 1940 (Folder 31: 55)
  - Zavrel, Jacques, Madame, 1937 (Folder 31: 56)
  - Zdziechowsky, Jerzy, 1952 (Folder 31: 57)
  - Zedwitz, Jiri, 1939 (Folder 31: 58)
  - Die Zeit, 1938 (Folder 31: 59)
  - Zelenka, F., n.d. (Folder 31: 60)
  - Zenkl, Petr, 1956-1961 (Folder 31: 61)
  - Zhanel, Rudolph, 1938-1939 (Folder 31: 62)
  - Zibrin, Michal, 1944 (Folder 31: 63)
  - Zídek, Emil Miloslav, 1939 (Folder 31: 64)
  - Zimmern, Alfred, 1940-1951 (Folder 31: 65)
  - Zucker, Herbert, 1937 (Folder 31: 66)
  - Die Zukunft, 1939-1940 (Folder 31: 67)
- Speeches and Writings, 1916-1971. (Box 32-68)
  Articles, notes, papers, radio broadcast transcripts, reports, speeches, and writings, arranged chronologically by title
  - General
    - Unidentified
      - General. Miscellaneous writings on a variety of subjects, n.d. (Folder 32: 1-11)
        Holographs
      - General. Miscellaneous writings on a variety of subjects, n.d. (Box-folder 33: 1-10)
      - General. Miscellaneous writings on a variety of subjects, n.d. (Box-folder 34: 1-5)
      - General. Miscellaneous writings on a variety of subjects, n.d. (Box-folder 35: 1-6)
      - General. Miscellaneous writings on a variety of subjects, n.d. (Box-folder 36: 1-6)
      - General. Miscellaneous writings on a variety of subjects, n.d. (Box-folder 37: 1-5)
      - General. Miscellaneous writings on a variety of subjects, n.d. (Folder 38: 1-5)
      - General. Miscellaneous writings on a variety of subjects, n.d. (Box-folder 39: 1-4)
      - Fragments (Folder 39: 5-9)
      - Fragments (Box-folder 40: 1-5)
      - Loose leaves (Folder 40: 6-10)
      - Notes (Folder 40: 11-12)
    - Untitled (Box 41)
      - American political philosophy, n.d. (Folder 41: 1)
        Holograph
      - American Slovaks, n.d. (Folder 41: 2)
        Holograph (in Slovak)
      - Aspects of the Allied policy and the role of the Czechoslovak Army in Russia after the Bolshevik Revolution, n.d. (Folder 41: 3)
        Holograph and typescript
      - Beneš, n.d. (Folder 41: 4-6)
        Holograph and typescript (in English, French and Czech)
      - Beneš' speech at the National Council meeting 1942 November 12, n.d. (Folder 41: 7)
      - Constitution of a Central European Commonwealth, n.d. (Folder 41: 8)
        Typescript
      - Diplomacy between World War I and World War II, n.d. (Folder 41: 9)
      - Europe, n.d. (Folder 41: 10)
      - Europe after World War II, n.d. (Folder 41: 11)
      - Geographic determination, n.d. (Folder 41: 12)
      - Georges Bernanos, n.d. (Box-folder 42: 1)
        Holograph (in French)
      - Germany, n.d. (Folder 42: 2)
      - Hitler, n.d. (Folder 42: 3)
      - Hodža, n.d. (Folder 42: 4)
      - Karl Marx and philosophy, n.d. (Folder 42: 5)
      - Masaryk, n.d. (Folder 42: 6)
      - Masaryk and his concept of revolution, n.d. (Folder 42: 7)
      - New world order, n.d. (Folder 42: 8)
      - The organized injustice the people of Czechoslovakia lived under, n.d. (Folder 42: 9)
      - Philosophy and religion, n.d. (Folder 42: 10)
      - Czechoslovak-Polish Confederation (Proposed), n.d. (Folder 42: 11)
      - Political and diplomatic relations between the Soviet Union and the Western powers, n.d. (Folder 42: 12)
        Typescript (in Slovak)
      - Reconstruction of Central and Eastern Europe, n.d. (Folder 42: 13)
      - The Roman Empire, n.d. (Folder 42: 14)
      - Russia, n.d. (Folder 42: 15)
      - Slovakia, n.d. (Folder 42: 16)
      - Štefánik, Milan R., n.d. (Folder 43: 1)
        Holograph and typescript (in English and Slovak)
      - World War I, n.d. (Folder 43: 2)
      - World War II and its political impact, n.d. (Folder 43: 3)
  - "Accord de Moscou," n.d. (Folder 43: 4)
    Typescript (in English)
  - "Adolf Hitler a naš odboj," radio speech broadcast, Czechoslovak Radio, n.d. (Folder 43: 5)
  - "Agriculture," n.d. (Folder 43: 6)
  - "Aksakov, Ivan," n.d. (Folder 43: 7)
  - "Aksakov, Konstantin," n.d. (Folder 43: 8)
  - "Aleksej S. Khomjakov," n.d. (Folder 43: 9)
  - "Alexandr I. Hertzen," n.d. (Folder 43: 10)
  - "Allied Political Warfare and Policy," n.d. (Folder 43: 11)
  - "America and Europe's Independence," radio broadcast, n.d. (Folder 43: 12)
  - "American Trade Unions and the European Crisis," n.d. (Folder 43: 13)
  - "Anniversary of a Popular Front," n.d. (Folder 43: 14)
    Notes and typescript
  - "Austria-Hungary," n.d. (Folder 43: 15)
  - "L'avenir de l'Europe Centrale," n.d. (Folder 43: 16)
  - "Bakunin and Marx," n.d. (Folder 43: 17)
  - "Bakunin, Michail," n.d. (Folder 43: 18)
  - "Un 'ballon-sonde' de Staline," n.d. (Folder 43: 19)
  - "The Bar under Communist Regimes," n.d. (Folder 43: 20)
  - "Barth, Karl," n.d. (Folder 43: 21)
  - "Bechyně a Osuský," n.d. (Folder 43: 22)
  - "Behaviors of USSR," n.d. (Folder 43: 23)
  - "Belinskii, Vissarion G.," n.d. (Folder 43: 24)
  - "Beneš: Liberation from Abroad," n.d. (Folder 43: 25)
  - "Beneš a pravda," n.d. (Folder 43: 26)
    Holograph and typescript (in Slovak)
  - "Beneš and Commitment," n.d. (Folder 43: 27)
  - "Beneš and France," n.d. (Folder 43: 28)
  - "Beneš and Soviet Russia," n.d. (Folder 43: 29)
  - "Beneš and the Czechoslovak Home Front," n.d. (Box-folder 44: 1)
  - "Beneš and the Dictators after Munich," n.d. (Folder 44: 2)
  - "Beneš Manipulator," n.d. (Folder 44: 3)
  - "Beneš's Government and the Slovak Home Front," n.d. (Folder 44: 4)
  - "Beneš's Government in London," n.d. (Folder 44: 5)
  - "Beneš's Perspective," n.d. (Folder 44: 6)
  - "Beneš's Philosophy for 1938," n.d. (Folder 44: 7)
  - "Beneš's Resignation," n.d. (Folder 44: 8)
  - "Benešova dvojjazyčnost," n.d. (Folder 44: 9)
    Holograph (in Czech)
  - "Benešova vláda a president Masaryk, n.d. (Folder 44: 10)
  - "Benešova vláda a Slováci," n.d. (Folder 44: 11)
  - "Berdiaev: The Origin of Russian Communism," n.d. (Folder 44: 12)
  - "Birth of the New Soviet Philosophy," n.d. (Folder 44: 13)
  - "Bloodless Conquest: Hitler's Method," n.d. (Folder 44: 14)
  - "Bohemia," n.d. (Folder 44: 15)
  - "Britain," n.d. (Folder 44: 16)
  - "Britain and China," n.d. (Folder 44: 17)
  - "Britain and Europe, n.d. (Folder 44: 18)
  - "Britain and Europe's Independence," radio broadcast, n.d. (Folder 44: 19)
  - "British and American Notions of Organized Europe," n.d. (Folder 44: 20)
  - "British Foreign Trade," n.d. (Folder 44: 21)
  - "The British View," n.d. (Folder 44: 22)
  - "Budapest," n.d. (Folder 44: 23)
  - "Čas dozrál," n.d., Typescript (in Czech and French) (Folder 44: 24)
  - "Causes of the Collapse: Wednesday, 1929 October 23," n.d. (Folder 44: 25)
  - "Celostátní výstava archívních dokumentů," n.d. (Folder 44: 26)
  - "Central Europe," n.d. (Folder 44: 27)
  - "Central European Federation and Security," n.d. (Folder 44: 28)
  - "Češi a Slováci," n.d. (Folder 44: 29)
  - "Češi, Slováci a podkarpatští Rusíni," speech, n.d. (Folder 44: 30)
  - "Češi, Slováci a Rusíni," speech, n.d. (Folder 44: 31)
  - "Československé drama," n.d. (Folder 44: 32)
  - "Československo a Polsko," n.d. (Folder 44: 33)
    Holograph and typescript (in Czech)
  - "Chernyshevskii, Nikolai," n.d. (Folder 44: 34)
  - "Childhood and Maturity," n.d. (Folder 44: 35)
  - "China and the Three Great Powers," n.d. (Folder 44: 36)
  - "Chování se vyslanců," n.d. (Folder 44: 37)
    Typescript (in Czech)
  - "Classical Marxism and K. Marx," n.d. (Folder 44: 38)
  - "La collaboration économique en Europe Centrale," n.d. (Folder 44: 39)
  - "The Collapse of Czechoslovakia: Events Leading to the Munich Agreement," n.d. (Folder 44: 40)
  - "Collectivization of Agriculture," n.d. (Folder 44: 41)
  - "Communism and Nationalism," n.d. (Folder 44: 42)
  - "Communism and Religion," n.d. (Folder 44: 43)
  - "Conservatism versus Socialism," n.d. (Folder 44: 44)
  - "Continuité de l'état tchécoslovaque," n.d. (Folder 44: 45)
  - "The Course of European Unification," n.d. (Folder 44: 46)
  - "The Crisis of the European Man," n.d. (Folder 44: 47)
  - "The Crucial Problem of the Cold War: Communist Encirclement of the Free Industrial Countries," n.d. (Folder 44: 48)
  - "ČSR. Sami se bránit nebudeme," n.d. (Folder 44: 49)
  - "Culture and Liberty," n.d. (Folder 44: 50)
  - "Czech Culture of Tomorrow," n.d. (Folder 44: 51)
  - "The Czech People and the Soviet-Czechoslovak Treaty," n.d. (Folder 44: 52)
  - "Czechoslovak Aims," n.d. (Box-folder 45: 1)
  - "Czechoslovak Justice?" n.d. (Folder 45: 2)
  - "Czechoslovak Problems," n.d. (Folder 45: 3)
  - "The Czechoslovak War Veterans in London and the Council of Free Czechoslovakia," n.d. (Folder 45: 4)
  - "Czechoslovakia's Role in the African Revolution," n.d. (Folder 45: 5)
    Holograph and typescript (in English and French)
  - "Czechoslovakia's Tragedy: A Proof of Kremlin's Permanent Revolution," n.d. (Folder 45: 6)
  - "Czechs and Slovaks Protest against New Napoleon," n.d. (Folder 45: 7)
  - "Danger and Opportunity," n.d. (Folder 45: 8)
  - "The Danubian Federation," n.d. (Folder 45: 9)
  - "Declaration," n.d. (Folder 45: 10)
  - "Defence of Our Country Is a Condition of Rights to Independence," n.d. (Folder 45: 11)
  - "Definition of Aggression," n.d. (Folder 45: 12)
  - "Did the New Replace the Old?" n.d. (Folder 45: 13)
  - "Discours par T.S.F. destiné aux Russes des Carpathes," n.d. (Folder 45: 14)
  - "Doctrines," n.d. (Folder 45: 15)
  - "Does Silence Speak?" n.d. (Folder 45: 16)
  - "Doom of the Soviet Satellite Empire," n.d. (Folder 45: 17)
  - "Dr. Beneš and Slovakia," n.d. (Folder 45: 18)
  - "Dr. Beneš Foreshadows Third World War," n.d. (Folder 45: 19)
  - "Dr. Beneš's Government Does not Touch Czech Hearts," n.d. (Folder 45: 20)
  - "Dr. Beneš's Presidency and Its Prolongation," n.d. (Folder 45: 21)
  - "Dr. Beneš's Secret Letter in the Hands of the German Gestapo," n.d. (Folder 45: 22)